Robert E. King Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Robert E. King Archives
1894-1952
IPAR.001070
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
1
The archives consist of annotated topographic maps of Texas (dated 1894-1929), stratigraphic sections from New Mexico and Texas, locality catalogs from Mexico (Sonora and Las Delicias), locality information from northern Africa (from his time with AOSP - American Overseas Petroleum), and negatives of brachiopods pictured in his dissertation.
King, Robert Evans
Biographical Sketch
Completed his PhD at Yale in 1929 ("Invertebrate faunas of the Permian of Trans-Pecos Texas")
Description of the Material
Includes some annotated maps from 1894-1929, as well as catalogs of localities, field photographs, stratigraphic sections, and a catalog of localities.
Connecticut; Texas; USA; Maps; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Maps, 1894-1929; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Topographic maps of Texas.
  - 1894-1915., 001074
    - Topographic map. Salt Basin, TX 30' Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1894; 001603
    - Topographic map. Alpine, TX 30' Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1895; 001604
    - Topographic map. Shafter, TX 30' Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1896; 001600
    - Topographic map. Cerro Alto, TX 30' Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001598
    - Topographic map. Van Horn, TX 30' Quad. (1: 125000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1906; 001599
  - 1916-1929., 001075
    - Location map. Hess Canyon, TX 15' Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1923; 001607
    - Map. Location map of measured sections: New Mexico, Texas,., 1929; 000215
    - Topographic map. Marathon, TX 15' Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1921; 001602
    - Topographic map. Monument Spring, TX 15' Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1921; 001605
    - Topographic map. Sierra Madera, TX 15' Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1923; 001601
    - Topographic map. Altuda, TX 15' Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1923; 001606
- Locality Information, Series II
  Robert E. Kings Locality Archives including locality information, catalogs of localities and stratigraphic sections.
  - Catalogs of Localities., 001078
    - Catalog of localities. Catalog of localities for Permian collections from Las Delicias: Mexico. 1926, 1933, 000274
    - Catalog of localities: Sonora, Mexico; manuscript by Dunbar and Norford, 000258
  - Locality Information., 001076
    - Locality information. locality information, Algeria, Paleozoic, 1952; 000866
    - Locality information. locality information, Tunisia, Paleozoic, 1952; 000867
    - Locality information. locality information, Algeria, Paleozoic, 1952; 000868
    - Locality information. locality information, Tunisia, Permian, 1952; 000869
    - Locality information. Locality information; Algeria; AOSP = American Overseas Petroleum Limited, 1954; 000228
  - Stratigraphic Sections., 001077
    - Locality information. Stratigraphic sections: Algeria; AOSP = American Overseas Petroleum Limited, 1954; 000229
    - Stratigraphic sections: New Mexico, Texas., 1935; 000231
- Miscellaneous, Series III
  - Photographs. Black & White negatives., 001079
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and white negatives of R.E. King's dissertation on Brachiopods Black and white negatives of brachiopods, 000603